I think deep down I know the answer.
其实我心里有答案
You probably do too.
你们应该也有了吧
But for some reason,
只是不知道为什么
there's still
我心里还有
a sliver of hope in me.
最后一丝希望
I'll handle
后面的事情
the investigation from here.
让我自己查吧
You've made many decisions
你已经做了很多选择
bringing us
我们才能走到
to this point.
今天这一步
You don't need
你没有必要
to face this
让自己面对
final part alone.
最后这个过程
I'll bring you back to the Shipyard.
我送你回造船所吧
No need.
不用了
I can drive now.
我已经学会开车了
It's my turn
今天
to take you back.
换我送你
You should head back and rest.
早点回去休息吧
I can drive the car in myself.
我自己把车开进去
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
When will you head back for Jiangyin?
你什么时候回江阴
Tomorrow.
明天
Go back.
回去吧
The Captain is right.
队长说得对
You don't need
你没有必要
to face this alone.
自己面对这个过程
I have a brother too.
我也有哥哥
If it were me,
如果换作是我
I'd feel the same.
我也会一样的
Although your brother
就算彭记者猜测是对的
was involved
你哥哥真的
as Mr. Peng speculated.
参与了这件事
This has nothing to do
那也是你的家庭
with yourself.
不是你
I'm leaving
我今天就要
for Jiangyin
跟着电雷学校
with the school today.
回江阴了
A new batch of
学校接收了
torpedo boats has arrived.
一批新的鱼雷艇
We need to bring them back.
我们要把鱼雷艇开回去
Got it.
明白
Go back and train well.
回去好好训练
I plan to
回去之后
take a leave to return to Nanjing.
我准备请假回南京
As Mr. Peng speculated,
如果彭记者的推测
if
是真的
my brother
我哥哥真的
was involved,
参与了那件事儿
taking money from Nakamura Naoki,
也收了里见直树的钱
then he must have kept ledgers
那他就一定会留下账本
and receipts.
还有票据
He wouldn't
这些东西
keep them
他不可能放在
in his office.
侍从室的办公室
He has a study at home.
他在家里有书房
That's our
这是离我们
closest lead.
最近的证据了
I'll check there,
等我回到南京的家
and come back to meet up with you.
我就来上海跟你会合
You came
你来找我
to tell me
是想告诉我
you're continuing the investigation?
你还要继续查下去
Yes.
对
Mr. Peng's is just a theory。
彭记者只是推测
I need to see the evidence with my eyes.
而我要亲眼看见证据
Unless I see proof
除非我亲眼看见
of their transaction,
他们交易的证据
I...
否则我
Do you understand
你知道走私
what smuggling
军需品
military supplies
对我们和日本
means for us and Japan?
意味着什么吗
Like tungsten ore.
就拿钨砂来说
It's a vital material
钨砂是非常重要的
for military manufacturing.
军工原料
China has abundant tungsten ore,
中国的钨砂产量丰富
whereas Japan has very little.
而日本的产量却很低
Japan's involvement in such smuggling
日本策动钨砂的走私
not only weakens our military capabilities
既削弱了国军的战斗力
but also aids
又可救济
their own struggling
陷于生产困境的
military industries.
日本军工业
That's killing two birds with one stone,
这么做一石二鸟
feeding the enemy.
是在给敌人输血
Even if my brother isn't a soldier,
即便我哥哥不是军人
he would clearly understand this.
他也一定清楚
I can't bring myself to believe
我实在不愿意相信
he's doing this.
他在做这种事
But tungsten mines
可是钨砂矿
are regulated
是国府军工部门
by our military departments.
在监管与控制
Without official involvement
如果没有官员的
and protection,
参与与包庇
it's impossible for these
这些矿物是不可能运到
to end up on Japanese ships.
日本的货船上的
Yesterday,
昨天我
after I returned from Mr. Peng's place
从彭记者那个地方
to the shipyard,
回到造船所
I sat up all night.
我坐了一晚上
I really don't want to believe
我实在不愿意相信
it's true.
这是真的
Chen Hao,
陈浩
I know you
我知道你
just want to be a good cop,
只想当一个好警察
staying out of politics.
不问政治
But resisting invasion
但我始终认为
isn't about politics.
抗日不是政治
This is clear
这一点
to all our citizens,
我们所有的民众都清楚
to the Communist Party that issued
发表《八一宣言》的
the August First Declaration.
共产党也清楚
But apparently not
可是我们的政府
to the government.
却不清楚
No,
不
they understand.
他们清楚
They just don't want to admit it.
只是不愿意承认
Do you remember
你还记不记得
asking me if I knew
你之前问过我
someone named
认不认识一个
Deng Mingyuan?
叫做邓铭远的人
You know him?
你认识他
More than that.
不只是认识
Mr. Deng has been like
邓先生对于我来说
a guiding star to me.
就像是启明星一样的人
5 years ago,
五年前
I graduated from the Police Academy
我从浙江警察学校毕业
and moved from a fishing village
然后从奉贤渔村
to Shanghai, becoming a policeman.
到了上海做警察
I was full of ambition,
有过踌躇满志
but also deeply disillusioned.
也有过万念俱灰
When I was struggling
在我挣扎
with whether to continue
要不要继续
being a cop,
做警察的时候
I met Mr. Deng,
认识了当时
who's then at
还在江南造船所的
Jiangnan Shipyard.
邓先生
He encouraged you to keep going?
是他让你坚持下去的
Yes.
对
Then, I was disheartened
那个时候我很灰心
'cause I felt that the Public Security Bureau
觉得公安局里的警察
weren't filled like the men
并不是我小时候
I dreamed of as a child.
梦想成为的那种警察
Mr. Deng always encouraged me
是邓先生一直鼓励我
to persevere,
他让我坚持
to continue doing
坚持做自己
what I believed was right.
认为正确的事情
Later, I learned
后来我才知道
he had joined the Communist Party.
他当时就加入了共产党
Do you know
你知道他为什么
why he did so?
要加入共产党吗
I asked him back then,
当时我问过老师
but he didn't tell me.
他没有告诉我答案
He said
邓先生说
smuggling
走私
was akin to committing suicide,
无异于自杀
a poison coated with honey.
是包着蜜糖的毒药
Consuming more of it
吃得越多
accelerates death,
死得越快
leading to defeat
不待战争
even before the war could do its damage.
就必趋于败亡的道路
The National Government has become
国民政府走到今天
powerless to rectify its roots.
已经无力正本清源
The soldiers following the past premier
当初跟着先总理北伐的
on the Northern Expedition
那些战士
have now become politicians
如今变成了政客
and financial moguls,
财阀
leaving the people in disarray
人民生活无着
while officials busy with privatizing
官员却在巧立名目
national assets!
化国为家
It's not a personal tragedy for Chiang,
这岂是蒋个人的悲剧
but for the entire government!
是整个国民政府的悲剧
So I understand
所以我理解
why Mr. Deng
我理解邓先生
joined the Communist Party.
为什么加入共产党
Because he and his comrades
因为他想和他的同志
wanted to build a new world.
建立一个新的世界
Chen Hao...
陈浩
I know
我知道
you're wondering
你想问
about my relationship with the Party.
我是不是共产党
I'm just a small-time cop,
我只不过是一名小警察
merely touched
只是偶然
by Mr. Deng's
被邓先生的星光
guiding light.
照亮过而已
When are you returning to Nanjing?
计划什么时候回南京
The day after tomorrow,
后天
the 30th of this month.
这个月三十号
Alright.
好
If there's any news,
如果有消息
call at 57331
三十号晚上十点
at 10 p.m.
打五七三三一这个电话
It's the number
这是我家附近
for the phone booth near my house.
电话亭的电话
I'll be there waiting for you.
我在那儿等你消息
Okay.
好
If not convenient, it's fine.
如果不方便也没关系
I'll continue the investigation in Shanghai.
我会在上海继续查下去
After all, he's your family.
毕竟那是你的家人
Nothing inconvenient.
没什么不方便
Just wait for my call.
等我电话吧
Alright.
好
We're here.
就是这里了
This is the last one
法租界一共
of the 3 safe houses
有三栋楼里面
of the NSO
有救国会的安全屋
in the French Concession.
这就是最后一栋
Sir,
先生
we're from
我们是
the beer company.
啤酒公司的
We've launched
我们公司最近
several new products
推出了几款新产品
and are looking for more customers.
想到您这儿拉拉客户
If we manage to sell,
要是能卖得出去的话
there would be a commission for you too.
这提成也有您的
Would it be
不知道
possible to see
方不方便
your tenant information?
看看您这儿的房客信息
Just a moment.
稍等啊
Sure.
好好好
The registration
这客人呢
here isn't complete.
登记得不全
Thank you.
谢谢
You might want to check
可以到房屋中介
with the housing agency.
再查查
Do you often
这公寓
have many residents here?
平常也不少住人吧
It's alight.
还行
See,
你看我这儿
I also brought some flyers.
还带了些传单
Since people come and go,
您这儿来来往往的
do us a favor for promotion.
也帮我们散一散
No problem.
好好好
Thank you.
多谢
Don't mention it.
应该的
Thank you for your work.
你这也挺辛苦的
Receiving your warning this morning,
早上收到你的警告通知
I immediately
我就马上
met with the leaders
和救国会负责人
of the NSO.
见了面
They also noticed
他们也发现
some unusual activities recently.
最近有些异常的情况
The NSO has rented rooms
救国会在法租界的
in several apartments
几栋公寓里
as safe houses
租了房做安全房
and even paid the porters
还给了门房酬劳
to alert them
说只要有人
if anyone inquires
来调查这些公寓
about them.
就马上打电话通知他们
Over the past two days,
最近两天
porters from
已经连续有
three buildings
三栋楼的门房
reported inquiries
汇报说
about landlord information,
有人在调查房东的信息
including the one for
包括了彭记者和彭太太
Mr. and Mrs. Peng.
住的那一栋
Do you know by whom?
知道什么人在调查吗
Ever since the Japanese military exerted pressure,
自从日本军方施压之后
secret controls on the NSO
针对救国会的秘密控制
have been increasing.
就越来越多
Could be by Shanghai Garrison Command
淞沪警备司令部
or the Secret Service
和复兴社特务处
of the Reviving Society.
这些都有可能
How are they
他们通过什么途径
getting the information?
查的房东姓名
Questioning porters
跟门房打听
or
还有
checking with housing agencies.
去法租界的中介调查
I'll take some actions.
我来想想办法吧
We might get the names
可能通过警务处
through the Police Service's connections
找到房屋中介
with the housing agencies.
能知道对方的名字
Immediately contact the NSO
你马上联络救国会
to move Mr. and Mrs. Peng
带彭记者彭太太
to a new location.
换个地方
Okay.
好
Jianshi once said
老乔说过
our team's task
我们小组的任务
was to work with the NSO.
就是统战救国会
If we can
如果这一次
help expose Mr. Peng's situation
我们可以帮助救国会
and the secrets
曝光彭记者的遭遇
they discovered,
和他们发现的秘密
it could not only alert the public
不仅能警醒民众
and deter the National Government
威慑国民政府
but also help us
还能帮助我们
achieve the united front's goals faster.
更快地达成统战的目标
However, we can't
但如果只靠
fully expose it
我们几个人和救国会
with just a few of us
是没有办法
and the NSO.
完全曝光出去的
Now I have a plan.
所以现在我有个计划
I'd like to propose to the higher-ups.
想向上级申请
What's the plan?
什么计划
I want to organize
想要组织安排人
a major rally
在江海关
at Shanghai Customs District
搞一次大型的集会
to force an
一是逼迫江海关
inspection of Nakamura Naoki's ships
调查里见直树的货船
and delay the smuggling of goods.
拖延这批走私品出港
Additionally, by rallying
二是通过集会和舆论
public opinion,
形成声浪
the larger the impact, the better.
影响越大越好
If your plan
如果你的计划
goes without a hitch,
能够顺利实施
then Mr. Peng and his wife
那彭记者和彭太太
become crucial witnesses.
就是重要的证人
That is why their safety
所以他们的安全
is paramount.
非常重要
How are you holding up?
你现在的情况怎么样
I've seen scout cars
我这几天晚上
searching for signals
都能看到侦察车
on the streets at night.
在街上来回地搜查信号
Yes.
对
I previously reduced the radio's power
我之前已经把电台功率
from 100 watts to 50,
从一百改到五十瓦
and recently from 50 to 15.
最近从五十改到了十五
15 watts...
十五瓦
With such a weak signal,
信号这么弱
can you still make contact?
能联系上吗
I used to
以前是
start working after the neighbors
等周围的居民睡下了
went to bed.
我就开始工作
Now I begin even later,
现在工作时间再晚一点
from midnight to four in the morning.
零点到四点
We'll have to
我们现在
split into three groups now.
只能兵分三路了
Be sure to keep yourself safe.
你自己一定要注意安全
Let's go.
走吧
Mrs. Ji,
季太太
I'm truly grateful for your care
这段时候承蒙您照顾
during this time.
感谢
We are all members of the NSO.
我们都是救国会的委员
It's natural for us to look out for each other.
互相照应是应该的
Take good care.
您多加小心
Is there a problem with this woman?
这女人有问题吗
Nothing.
没事儿
Is this also an NSO house?
这间也是救国会的房子
Yes.
是的
I found from the agency
我在中介上查到
that the tenant of this room
这间房子的租客
and one
和我掌握的
of the names
救国会上的
on my NSO list
名单的一个人
are brothers.
是亲兄弟
I knew this building
我原先知道这栋楼里
had their safe house.
有他们的安全房
Now I'm sure
现在可以肯定
this room
这间
is it.
就是他们的安全房
Using the same method,
我通过同样的方法
I found two other safe houses
在法租界另外两栋楼里
in two other buildings
查到了他们的
in the French Concession.
另外两间安全房
Someone
不久之前
was here before.
有人用过
Are those two rooms
另外两间房子也一样
also needs monitoring?
派人盯着
Absolutely.
必须盯
Since Hua Zhen rescued
华桢不是救了
someone from the NSO,
救国会的人吗
it's very likely
救了人
they would use
就太有可能用到
these safe houses.
这些安全房了
Have someone watch them,
你派人盯着
and alert me immediately if anyone enters.
任何人进来马上通知我
Mr. Wei,
魏先生
aren't we casting
我们这样撒网
our net too wide?
范围会不会太大了
Not at all!
一点儿都不大
You have to trust me,
你们要相信我
I've been battling the Communists
我跟共产党
for six to seven years.
已经斗了六七年了
You brought me in for this job,
你们请我来做这件事情
and you need to trust my instinct.
就一定要相信我的直觉
We are
我们已经
getting closer.
距离越来越近了
What's the matter?
怎么了魏先生
Something's off.
不对
For the woman
我们路上
we just saw,
碰到的那个女的
I'm sure I've seen her somewhere.
我总觉得在哪儿见过
Recently?
最近吗
Must have been.
应该是
Think about where you've been frequently
那您想想来特务处之前
before coming to the Special Service.
您最近常去哪些地方
The tailor's.
裁缝铺
I saw her
我在裁缝铺
at the tailor's shop.
见过那个女的
Sir,
先生
may I ask
受累跟您打听一下
if a woman
刚刚有没有一个
wearing a hat and a scarf
戴帽子戴围巾的女的
just came out of here,
从这里走出来
about this tall?
差不多这么高
Should be.
好像有一个
Are you sure
你确定她是从
she came out
这栋公寓楼里
of this apartment building?
走出来的吗
As a doorman,
我们做门房的
I watch
整天啊
people coming
就是看着你们
and going all day.
在这里进进出出的
She seemed
跟她在一起的
to be with
好像
two other people.
好像还有两个人
Which room does she live in?
她住哪个房间啊
I don't know that.
这就不知道了
It's her.
就是她
I remembered correctly.
果然没记错
I knew
我就知道
Zhang Runjin's Communist associates
张润金的共产党同伙
were around this area.
在这个附近
I saw her before.
我当时见过这个女的
Now she's showing up
现在她又出现在
near an NSO safe house.
救国会的安全屋附近
That can't be a coincidence.
这怎么可能是巧合
Should we bring her in for questioning?
抓她回去审吗
Of course not.
不 不 不
She's just a lead.
她只是线头
Our real target
最终的目标
is to draw out Hua Zhen.
是要牵出华桢
Be patient.
耐点儿心
We still have a lot of work to do,
我们还有很多工作要做
but we are getting closer.
但是已经越来越近了
Dad,
对了 爸爸
another day is coming.
后天就是一号了
I need to go to Wusong Port.
我要去趟吴淞口
Don't ask me about business.
生意上的事不要问我
Just handle it yourself.
自己处理就行了
Okay, I got it.
行 我知道了
I'm heading out.
那我走了啊
Did your brother's trip
你弟弟
to Shanghai go smoothly?
这回去上海一切顺利
It did.
顺利
Is the guy who arrested him
上次抓他那个人
still causing trouble?
还在找他麻烦吗
You mean Wei Daiqing?
你说魏岱擎啊
He's been fired.
他早都被开除了
Don't worry,
您放心吧
I've handled all his troubles
他在上海的麻烦
in Shanghai.
我都解决了
I just heard
我刚才
you tell your dad
听你跟你爸爸说
that you've arranged everything.
你都已经安排好了
What's that?
安排什么呀
Don't worry about it.
这个您就别操心了
Rest assured,
别管了
I'll handle it.
我都会处理好的
Liang,
梁儿
you know
你知道
I've always
我对你弟弟
felt guilty about your brother.
一直心有亏欠
You're
从小到大
raised by
你始终
your dad and me,
由我和你爸爸带在身边
but Zhen wasn't.
但是桢儿没有
You only bring us good news
你对你弟弟的事情
about him
从来报喜不报忧
and I don't ask much.
我也不多问了
But
但是
no matter what happens,
不管发生任何事情
remember,
你要记着
you're brothers.
他是你弟弟
Mom. Don't worry,
知道了妈妈 放心吧
as long as he has no ties
只要他跟共产党
to the Communists,
没有瓜葛
no one dares touch him.
没有人敢动他
Young Master is back.
二少爷回来了
Here,
来
have some soup
趁热
while it's still hot.
先喝点儿汤
What brought you back so suddenly?
怎么突然就回来了
School gave us a break,
学校给我们放假
so I thought
我就想着
I'd come to see you all.
回来看看你们
Where's my brother?
我哥呢
He's not in Nanjing,
他不在南京啊
left for Shanghai
昨天刚走
yesterday.
去上海了
Need him for something?
怎么 你找他有事儿啊
I wanted him
我想让他
to bring me a record
从上海帮我
from Shanghai.
带一张唱片回来
Which hotel he's staying at?
你知道他住哪个饭店吗
I'll call him.
我给他打电话
He's gone
他是去
to the Wusong Port freight terminal,
吴淞口的货运站了
not staying in the city.
不在城里
Drink your soup before it gets cold.
快喝汤吧 都凉了
Alright.
好
Young Master,
二少爷
do you need the study of Mr. Hua Liang?
您要用大少爷的书房吗
I'll read for a while.
我先看会儿书
You can come in and clean later.
一会儿再进来打扫吧
Okay.
好的
May 1st,
五月一日
196,000 yuan;
十九万六千元
July 1st,
七月一日
130,000 yuan;
十三万元
September 1st,
九月一日
139,000 yuan;
十三万九千元
November 1st,
十一月一日
123,000 yuan;
十二万三千元
February 1st,
二月一日
162,000 yuan;
十六万两千元
May... July...
五月 七月
September... November...
九月 十一月
Hello,
喂
this is Chen Hao.
我是陈浩
I looked at my brother's ledger.
我看了我哥的账本
Every two months on the first,
每两个月的一号这一天
he receives
他会收到一笔入账
a large deposit.
数额很大
Following this pattern,
按照这个规律
the next payment
下个月的一号
should be tomorrow.
也就是明天
He's now at Wusong Port.
他现在去了吴淞口
I suspect
我估计
it's related to
就是彭记者
what Mr. Peng mentioned.
提到的那事儿
I checked with the shipping company.
我从航运公司查到了
The Shinei Maru,
彭记者当时
the Japanese cargo ship
在十六铺码头
Mr. Peng photographed
拍到的那艘
at Shiliupu Wharf,
新荣丸号日本货轮
is scheduled to dock there
下个月六号
on the sixth of next month.
会在十六铺码头进港
Payment on the first,
一号交易
shipment on the sixth,
六号装船
the timing matches perfectly.
时间正好对得上
I've requested leave from school.
我已经跟学校请了假
I'll head to Wusong Port tomorrow.
明天出发去吴淞口
Okay,
好
be careful.
注意安全
I often look back when I'm abroad,
我一身去国常回顾
intending to return
若使齐事了
once my duty is fulfilled.
便归乡土
But with the nation in such disarray,
如今国将不国
my homeland no longer feels the same.
乡土 也难为乡土
I deeply understand what all this
我深知这一切
means for my family,
对华家意味着什么
but how can one support
可大厦将倾
a falling nation alone?
一木怎扶
With the national crisis at hand,
国难当头
some people are arresting
这些人一边逮捕
patriots who resist invasion
抗日的爱国人士
while simultaneously smuggling
一边走私军需品
military supplies to the enemy.
给日本人
Who is truly saving the nation,
究竟是谁在救国
and who is harming it?
又是谁在害国
A week ago,
一个星期之前
Japan pressured Shanghai
日方向沪施压
to dissolve the NSO.
要求解散救国会
So, your most
所以你现在
important task now
最重要的任务
is to find concrete evidence
是找到证据
proving that the 3 people in the photo
确切地证明照片三个人
were smuggling military supplies.
在往日本走私军需品
I'll report our current findings
我会马上向组织
to the organization immediately.
汇报现在的情况
I plan to continue investigating
我准备去江海关
at the Customs District.
继续查查看
Also,
另外
Xiang Yuansheng has decided
向远生也决定
to pursue his inquiries.
继续查下去
He's already
他已经出发
departed to Wusongkou,
去吴淞口的路上了
where he believes Hua Liang
他查到华梁在那儿
will engage in new transactions.
会有新的交易
Xiang Yuansheng
向远生说
wanna continue investigating?
他打算继续查下去
I thought he might stop,
我也以为他会停手
given it's his family involved.
那毕竟是他的家人
But he's adamant.
但他很坚持
He argues that resisting invasion
他说抗日
shouldn't be politicized,
不应该是政治
and he's aware
他还知道
of our August First Declaration.
我们的《八一宣言》
After issued,
《八一宣言》发表之后
it resonated deeply
在国统区
within the KMT controlled area,
引起了很大的反响
receiving support from all walks
社会各阶层人士
on halting the civil war
都在支持我们停止内战
and uniting together.
一致抗日的主张
If we can
如果能够
expose this smuggling case,
顺利曝光走私案
it could greatly influence the movement
一定能对抗日救亡运动
to save the nation.
起到巨大作用
He knows that,
他知道
and that's why
就是因为他知道
he made his decision.
他才做了这个决定
My superiors tasked me
上级给了我任务
to observe if Xiang Yuansheng
让我观察向远生
could potentially join us
有没有可能发展成为
as a comrade,
我们的同志
and I've already made my decision.
我心里已经有了答案
If I am
如果我是一根火柴
but a spark,
可以燃烧一时
he could be
那么他就是有可能
a blazing bonfire.
成为熊熊篝火的人
If he shows
只要他现在
willingness now,
主动提出意愿
I'll immediately propose to the leadership
我会马上向上级申请
to recruit him.
发展他加入我们
You want to encourage him
你想用这种方式
in this way?
来鼓励他
Exactly.
对
The situation now
事情发展到现在
is devastating
对他来说无疑是
for him.
毁灭性的打击
Just as Mr. Deng
当初邓先生
once guided me with his light,
用他的星光照亮我
I hope
我也希望
to offer him some hope
在他最艰难的时候
during his darkest moments.
给他一些希望
I will report
我会向上级汇报
your observations of him.
你对他的观察结果
Moreover,
另外
I've always felt
我一直觉得
that Mr. Deng and we
邓先生和我们
are idealists
在某种意义上来说
in a sense.
都是理想主义者
It's difficult for one
不然一个人很难
to persevere through the darkest times
从组织被摧毁
when the organization
所有人被打散的
is shattered
至暗时刻
and all are scattered.
坚持下来
Mr. Deng recruited you,
组长发展你
not just as an encouragement
既是一个理想主义者
from one idealist
对另一个理想主义者的
to another
鼓励
but because you're trustworthy.
也因为你值得
As an underground intelligence officer,
作为地下情工
your skills may not be the best,
你的技能的确不算最好
but the flame
但你心里
of idealism in your heart
有团理想的火苗
has never extinguished.
从未熄灭
That's what truly matters.
这才是最重要的
Yu, wait up,
小玉 等我一下
I'll come with you to the warehouse.
我跟你一块儿去趟仓库
With the heavy rain and your injured hand,
这么大雨 你手还伤着
you should stay home.
你在家等我吧
I'll clean up and be right back.
我去打扫了就回来
I know you're scared of walking alone
我怕你一个人走夜路
at night,
会害怕
and I also want
刚好我也想
to get familiar with the warehouse.
去熟悉熟悉仓库
Let me come with you.
你就让我去吧
What's the rush?
哪儿有那么着急啊
We still have to wait for the goods
还要等你从金山卫
from Jinshanwei
拉货回来
before discussing the warehouse
才能跟经理商量
with the manager.
看仓库的事儿
If I get to know
我早点儿去
the warehouse earlier,
熟悉熟悉仓库
I can make
见了经理
a good impression.
才能够好好表现
I really want
这次的差事
to secure this job,
我一定要争取下来
otherwise everyone
要不然他们总操心我
keeps worrying about me,
这也不是事儿吧
is it?
是吧
Alright,
知道了
let's go.
走吧
Lock the door.
记得关门啊
Is Mr. Xu not around?
徐伯伯是不是不在呀
The window under his control
我看他管的一号仓库
wasn't closed.
窗户也没有关
He's on vacation.
他放假了
Someone rented
前段时间
that warehouse,
有人租了一号仓库
with their own manager brought in.
要换成自己的管理员
So the manager told Mr. Xu
经理就让徐伯伯
to stay away for a while.
这段时间先不来了
Okay,
行
after we finish up here,
那咱干完这点儿活
let's close it up for him.
也帮他那个关了吧
We owe our jobs
你说咱能在码头
at the docks
找着工作
to Mr. Xu's introduction.
全靠徐伯伯介绍
If his goods get wet,
他那点儿货淋湿了
they'll dock his pay, right?
他也得扣工钱不是
Right.
行
With it raining this hard,
这雨下这么大
the goods inside must be getting damaged.
里边的货肯定得淋坏
Anybody there?
仓库有人吗
Hello?
有人吗
Is someone here?
一号仓库有人管吗
Wait here a minute.
你在这儿等我一会儿
I'll go up and check.
我上去检查一下
Be careful.
你小心点儿
Don't worry, leave it to me.
没事儿 你不用上
I can handle it.
我自己就行
Take it slow.
慢着点儿
Careful!
小心点儿
It's okay.
没事儿
Just a box fell.
有个箱子掉了
Really, be careful.
你慢着点儿